soundclick.com 2019-07-01

# Legal

July, 2003. Last modified May 25, 2018.

Privacy Statement

SoundClick is committed to protecting your privacy online. We are also committed to providing you with the very best experience we can on our Web site. In order to enhance your experience at our site we gather certain personal information about you that helps us customize our content to your tastes and preferences. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our Web site. This policy may change from time to time so please check back periodically. 

What information do we collect?

SoundClick collects information in several ways from different parts of our Web site. SoundClick collects some personal information when you initially sign up for some of our services. We may ask for your name, e-mail address, zip code, and country. The more information you share with us (and the more accurate it is), the better we are able to enhance and customize your experience on our site. 

In addition to the former information, we may ask you for personal information at other times, including (but not limited to) when you make a purchase through our online store, when you enter promotions or contests and when you respond to a survey. For example, when you make a purchase through our online store, we collect several items of personal information, including your billing and shipping address, telephone number, credit card information, PayPal account email, and any other information necessary to complete the transaction. For your security, we never store credit card information on our servers. We transmit credit card information directly to the third party credit card processor through secure connections, and PayPal-related information directly to PayPal. You may find out more about [PayPal's privacy policy](https://www.paypal.com/va/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) on their linked privacy policy page. 

We automatically collect log information when you use our site or services, even if you have not registered for an account or logged in. That information may include, among other things: details about how you've used our site or services, Internet Protocol (IP) address, access times, your browser type and operating system, device information, device event information (e.g., crashes, browser type), and the page you've viewed or engaged with before or after using our site or services. 

We may collect data about your general location (e.g. your IP address). We may use this data to provide you with location-based services (such as advertising and personalized content). Most mobile devices allow you to control or disable the use of location services for applications in the device's settings. 

What are "cookies" and how do we use them?

SoundClick uses "Cookies" to track and record your preferences and activity on our Web site. Cookies are small bits of data that are sent to your browser and stored on your computer's hard drive. Your cookie may be set at various times during your interaction with our Web site. It is updated from time to time as you access the many different portions of our Web site. Each time you access our site, our server may deliver certain customized information to you based on the data stored in your cookie. 

Some advertisers or Web sites that have links on our site may also use their own cookies. If you do not wish to allow for use of cookies, you can generally opt-out of providing this information by setting your browser to reject cookies. However, please be aware that some areas may not provide you with an acceptable user experience if you have disabled the use of cookies. 

In addition, if we feel that a user abuses the SoundClick site in any way, we reserve the right to share certain information with third parties. Abuses include (but are not limited to) possible copyright infringement, possible libel and slander, possible credit card fraud. 

Third party cookies

We use technologies, such as cookies, to customise content and advertising, to provide social media features and to analyse traffic to the site. We also share information about your use of our site with our trusted social media, advertising and analytics partners. 

We enable 3rd party cookies by Google to track users for statistical analysis through Google Analytics. You can find out more about their policy and how to opt out on [Google Analytics data privacy and security](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/181881?hl=en&ref_topic=2919631) page. 

We also use 3rd party cookies by Quantcast to track users for statistical analysis. You may [opt out of Quantcast's](https://www.quantcast.com/opt-out/) tracking. 

We use Facebook as optional way to sign up or to log in to your acount. The information we receive to facilitate this single-sign on may include your Facebook user ID, first name, last name, email address, gender, locale, your time zone, birthday, and profile picture. In addition we utilize social-media features such as sharing or liking SoundClick content through Facebook. You may find out more about [Facebook's privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php) on their linked privacy policy page. 

What additional information do parties other than SoundClick collect?

To provide our services in a safe and efficient manner we utilize some third party services for security reasons, infractructure, traffic routing, or site optimization. These third parties may collect personally identifiable information about you when you access our site or services. Data collection mostly consists of information such as IP addresses, physical location, and access to resources. These service providers have access to your information solely to perform these tasks on our behalf, and are contractually bound to implement appropriate organizational and technical security measures to protect against unauthorized disclosure of personal data, and only to process personal data in accordance with our instructions and to the extent necessary to provide their services to us. 

We publish public profile information e.g. through the use of open graphs. These social-media features fall under the privacy policies of the companies that utilize open graphs and similar. You may find out more about [Facebook's privacy policy](https://www.facebook.com/policy.php), and you may find out more about [Twitter's privacy policy](https://twitter.com/en/privacy) on their respective linked privacy policy pages. 

With whom do we share your information and for what purpose?

SoundClick does not sell, rent, or trade your personal information with others. However, when one or more of our business partners co-sponsor a service, promotion and/or contest, we may share some or all of the information collected in connection with such service, promotion or contest with the co-sponsor(s). If you do not want your information to be shared, you will be able to choose not to allow the transfer by not using or signing up for that particular service, promotion or contest. 

In addition, when you make a purchase through our online store, or sign up to receive promotional items from us, we may share some of your personal information with third parties helping us to complete your transaction or send you the items you signed up to receive. When we share your information with such third parties, we will work to ensure that only the information necessary to complete your transaction is disclosed. 

Managing your personal information with us

You control the personal data you share with us. You can access or rectify this data at any time. You can also deactivate your account. We also provide you tools to object, restrict, or withdraw consent where applicable for the use of data you have provided to us. 

Data portability: You can receive a copy of the personal information we collected about you by requesting such a collection via email from us at support@soundclick.com. 

Accessing or rectifying your personal data: If you have registered an account on SoundClick, we provide you with tools and account settings to access, correct, delete, or modify the personal data you provided to us and associated with your account. Where you cannot update data yourself through an account, you have the right to ask us to correct change, update or rectify your data. 

Deletion ("right to be forgotten"): We generally retain data for as long as your account is in existence or as needed to provide our service. You have the right to ask us to delete all or some of the personal data we hold about you. If you have an account, you request deletion of your account via email to support@soundclick.com. We may need to retain some of your personal data even after you have closed your account if reasonably necessary to comply with our legal obligations, or where we have a legitimate interest in doing so (e.g. to prevent fraud and abuse and maintain and enhance security). Also, keep in mind that search engines and other third parties may still retain copies of your public information, like your user profile information, even after you have deleted the information from SoundClick. 

Objection to processing: You may object to processing your personal information in some circumstances (in particular, where we don't have to process the information to meet legal requirement). If you object to such processing we will no longer process your personal information unless we have legitimate grounds for such processing or such processing is required for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims or obligations. 

Your Consent

By using our Web site, you consent to the collection and use of your personal information by SoundClick as outlined in this Privacy Policy. 

Changes to our Privacy Policy

From time to time, we may change our Privacy Policy. We will post those changes on this page so that our customers will always be aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we share the information with others.
